[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So next let's discuss what does over-fitting look like for a classifier.
دﻋوﻧﺎ ﻧﻧﺎﻗش كيف ﯾبدو التناسق باستخدام المصنف.
So we talked about a wide range of classifiers, so for
لقد تحدثنا عن مجموعة كبيرة من المصنفات،
example here I am fitting a linear classifier to the data and it's our usual
فعلى سبيل المثال، هنا أقوم بالتصنيف الخطي للبيانات على المثال المألوف بالنسبة لنا
example with predicting that their review is positive or negative for a restaurant.
المعني بتوقع إيجابية أو سلبية المراجعات للمطعم.
And so we see that the points below the line have score greater than 0.
كما نرى فالنقاط الموجودة أسفل الخط تحتوي على قيم أكبر من 0.
The points above the line have scored less than 0.
وتحتوي النقاط فوق الخط على قيم أقل من 0.
So below the line I predict as positive, above the line I predict as negative.
فإن كانت النقاط تحت الخط تصبح القيم إيجابية، وإن كانت فوق الخط تصبح سلبية.
And you get this very, very simple line in this simple example.
لتحصل على هذا الخط البسيط للغاية في هذا المثال البسيط.
For this module I've created a simple data set shown here on the lower left with
في هذه الوحدة، قمت بإنشاء مجموعة بيانات بسيطة معروضة هنا في أسفل اليسار
positive and negative examples and I want to fit a bunch of different reference
مع الأمثلة الإيجابية والسلبية وأريد إرفاق مجموعة مصنفات مرجعية مختلفة
classifiers to it to really observe how over-fitting happens in practice.
لنلاحظ حقا كيف يحدث التناسق في الواقع.
So first, I'm going to fit a simple classifier with a linear feature so
أولاً، سأرفق مصنّفًا بسيطًا بخاصية خطية
it's just the constant that is zero,
والثابت هو الوحيد بقيمة صفر،
the coefficient of x1 which is going to be w1 and
ومعامل x1 سيصبح w1
the coefficient of x2 which is going to be w2 and if I
ومعامل x2 سيصبح w2
learn the logistical rational classifier in this data I get the following results.
وإذا تعلمت المصنف العقلاني اللوجستي في هذه البيانات، فسأحصل على النتائج التالية.
The constant becomes 0.23 the co-efficient of x one becomes one point twelve and
ليصبح الثابت 0.23، ويصبح 1.12 معامل x1
the co-efficient of x two becomes minus 1.07.
ويصبح 1.07 معامل x2.
So, on the right here I'm showing the resulting decision boundary
إذاً، على اليمين هنا، أعرض حدود القرار
from this classifier.
الناتج عن هذا المصنف
So, this line here corresponds to
لذلك، فهذا الخط هنا يتوافق مع
the point where 0.23 plus 1.12
النقطة حيث 0.23 زائد 1.12
x 1 minus 1.
x 1 ناقص 1.
Let's clear that a little bit, minus 1 point
دعونا نوضح ذلك قليلا، ناقص 1.07
07, x2 is equal to 0.
x2 يساوي 0.
So this is our observation of that transition from the points
إذن تلك هي ملاحظتنا للانتقال من النقاط
down here where the Score(x) is greater than 0 and
الموجودة بالأسفل حيث Score(x) أكبر من 0
the points over here where the Score(x) is less than zero.
والنقاط الموجودة بالأعلى حيث درجة Score(x) أقل من الصفر.
So the points above that line in predicting is being negative points and
وبالتالي فإن النقاط فوق هذا الخط هي نقاط سلبية للتنبؤ
the points below the line is predicting them to be positive.
والنقاط تحت الخط إيجابية للتنبؤ.
And you see some interesting things in this simple
لنر بعض الأشياء المثيرة للاهتمام في مجموعة البيانات البسيطة التي أمامنا
data set with just a simple classifier.
باستخدام مصنف بسيط لا غير.
You see that the, and this is a pretty decent job of separating the positives
سترى هنا، في هذا المجهود اللائق جدًا لفصل الإيجابيات
from the negatives but there are a few points here where they are mis-classified
عن السلبيات، أن هناك بضع نقاط مصنفة بشكل خاطئ
in the training data so this plus is over here and this minus is over here.
في بيانات التدريب بحيث يكون هذا الموجب هنا وهذا السالب هنا.
And the question is, can I do better?
والسؤال هو، هل يمكنني ترقية الوضع نوعًا ما؟
Can I fit a model with maybe slightly fancier features
هل يمكنني ملاءمة نموذج يحتوي على ميزات أكثر
that does better on this data set?
بحيث يعمل بشكل أفضل على مجموعة البيانات التي أمامنا؟
To fit our data model, I'm going to try now what are called quadratic features.
لملاءمة نموذج البيانات لدينا، سأحاول الآن ما يسمى بالميزات التربيعية.
So, I'm going to consider, not just one, x1, and x2, but
لذا، سأدرس، ليس فقط x1 و x2،
I'm also going to consider x1 squared, and x2 squared.
بل أيضًا مربع x1، ومربع x2.
Note that this is not general quadratic features, and not considering x1
لاحظ أن هذه ليست ميزات تربيعية عامة، ولا تعنى بضرب x1
times x2 or the cross terms, because then they becomes pretty big.
في x2 أو في العناصر المتقاطعة، فبذلك ستصبح تلك العناصر كبيرة جدًا.
Later on so I'm just going to do this simple quadratic feature.
لاحقًا، سأقوم فقط بهذه الميزة التربيعية البسيطة.
And if I learn a classifier on the same data,
وإذا تعلمت المصنفات على نفس البيانات،
I get a really cool decision boundary.
فسأحصل على حدود مذهلة للقرارات.
And then the decision boundary, when I project it
ومن ثم حدود القرار، عندما أعرضها
into this two-dimensional space, becomes this kind of curved parabola.
في هذا الفضاء ثنائي الأبعاد، تتمثل في هذا النوع من القطع المكافئ المنحني.
So the coefficient in this case of The constant becomes 1.68,
وبالتالي فإن معامل الثابت في هذه الحالة يصبح 1.68،
x1 is 1.39, x2 is -0.59.
و x1 هو 1.39 و x2 هو -0.59.
Both of these numbers are different from the ones on
كل من هذه الأرقام مختلفة عن تلك الموجودة
the previous slide because the parameters are all updated.
في الشريحة السابقة نظرًا لتحديث جميع المتغيرات.
Within this view of the quadratic terms and
ضمن هذا المنظر الممثل للمصطلحات التربيعية
here the quadratic terms become minus 0.17 and minus 0.96.
هنا تصبح المصطلحات التربيعية سالب 0.17 وسالب 0.96.
And using this quadratic terms I get this beautiful
وباستخدام تلك العناصر التربيعية، أحصل على
quadratic decision boundary over here which basically
الحدود التربيعية المتناسقة التي أمامنا
says that 1.68 plus 1.39 X1 minus 0.59x2
والتي توضح أن 1.68 زائد 1.39 X1 ناقص 0.59x2
minus 0.17x1 squared minus 0.96x2 squared.
ناقص مربع 0.17x1 ناقص مربع 0.96x2.
This whole thing is equal to zero, and
كل هذا يساوي صفرًا
the points now, on the left side of the parabola,
وتصبح النقاط الآن، الموجودة على الجانب الأيسر من القطع المكافئ،
are the ones that have Score(x), be less than 0 and
هي النقاط التي تحتوي على Score(x)، أقل من 0
the points on the right side here are those
والنقاط على اليمين هنا هي النقاط
where a score of x is greater than 0.
حيث درجة x أكبر من 0.
And you get this beautiful curve where yes you still make a couple of mistakes but
لنحصل على هذا المنحنى المتناسق حيث لا يزال هناك بعض الأخطاء
I tell you, those mistakes seem okay to me.
لكن بالنسبة لي، تلك الأخطاء تبدو معقولة.
The data pre-well you should never expect for real data sets.
يجب ألا تتوقع أبدا وجود البيانات المتناسقة في العالم الواقعي
For everything like, in fact, as we will see later in this module,
في أي مجال، بل إننا سنرى في هذه الوحدة
getting everything right should be a big sign of warning for you.
أن إحراز الدقة المتناهية قد يدعوك للشك.
But I get pretty good fit and it looks beautiful and
لكني هنا أرى تناسقًا جيدًا
note, by the way, that the coefficients that I learn over here are pretty good.
لاحظ، بالمناسبة، أن المعاملات التي أتعلمها هنا جيدة للغاية.
They look like a natural magnitude, about one, 0.5, and so on.
فهي تبدو كمقياس طبيعي، للأرقام التقريبية مثل واحد، و 0.5 وما إلى ذلك.
Now let's see what happens when you do an even higher degree polynomial.
الآن دعونا نرى ما يحدث عندما نتعامل مع كثيرات الحدود من الدرجة الأعلى.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]